gay.com 2019-12-29

# Privacy Policy - Los Angeles LGBT Center

**PRIVACY POLICY**

Effective Date: February 5, 2016.

**To download/print our Privacy Policy, click[here](https://vanguardnow.org/images/Policy_PDFs/PRIVACY%20POLICY%20PDF.pdf). To download/print our Terms of Service, click [here](https://vanguardnow.org/images/Policy_PDFs/TERMS%20PDF.pdf).**

**Overview**

You should read this entire Privacy Policy, but here is a partial list of some of the key topics. Any capitalized terms have the meanings given to them where defined in the Privacy Policy.

  * We ask you for, and use Tracking Technologies (defined below) to detect information about you, and third parties may also do so in connection with our Services (defined below), including to send you ads when you leave our Service. Click [here](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section6) for details.
  * Third parties, including advertisers and advertising services providers, may collect information about you. They may use Tracking Technologies in connection with our Service, which may include the collection of information about your online activities over time and across third-party sites or services. Their privacy policies, not ours, govern their practices.
  * We do not monitor or take any action with respect to so-called browser “do not track” signals, but you may have certain other options regarding tracking and/or targeting.
  * You consent to our practices detailed in our Privacy Policy. Each time you use the Services, the version of our Privacy Policy then posted will apply to that use, subject to [Section 11](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section11), so you should check back each time you return for updates. To prospectively change your consent, terminate your account and stop using the Service.
  * We may from time to time elect to share certain information about you collected by us on the Service or offline with third parties as part of a cooperative database with those third parties and for those third parties’ direct marketing and/or charitable solicitation purposes, but we provide you an opportunity to opt-out. Click [here](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3i) for details and [Your California Privacy Rights](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3i).

See also our [Terms of Service](https://vanguardnow.org/images/Policy_PDFs/TERMS%20PDF.pdf) and [Notice of Privacy Practices for Protected Health Information](https://lalgbtcenter.org/images/Downloads/HS1310ENG.pdf) and [Notificación Sobre Normas de Privacidad para Información de Salud Protegidapara Información de Salud Protegida](https://lalgbtcenter.org/images/Downloads/HS1315ESP.pdf).

**Introduction**

Welcome! You have arrived at a website and/or are otherwise interacting with our Service (defined below), which is owned and operated by the Los Angeles LGBT Center ( **“The Center,” “we,” “our,”** or **“us”** ). This **“Privacy Policy”** governs your use of any online service location (e.g., web site or mobile app) that posts a link to this Privacy Policy (each a **“Site”** ) (including both mobile and online versions). It also applies to your use of all features, widgets, plug-ins, applications, content, downloads and/or other services (i) we own and control and make available through a Site, and/or (ii) that post a link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, the **“Service”** ), regardless of how you access or use them, whether via personal computer, mobile device or otherwise, but does not apply to data we receive from third parties unless we combine such data with Personal Information (defined below) that we have ourselves collected under this Privacy Policy. This Privacy Policy does not apply to our data collection activities offline or otherwise outside of our Service (unless otherwise stated below), and does not govern the data practices of third parties that may interact with our Service. For our privacy practices regarding your protected healthcare information see [Notice of Privacy Practices for Protected Health Information](https://lalgbtcenter.org/images/Downloads/HS1310ENG.pdf) and [Notificación Sobre Normas de Privacidad para Información de Salud Protegidapara Información de Salud Protegida](https://lalgbtcenter.org/images/Downloads/HS1315ESP.pdf).

To the extent we provide you notice on our Service of different or additional privacy policies or practices (e.g., at the point of our collection), those additional terms shall govern such data collection and use.

In addition, please review the Service’s [Terms of Service](https://lalgbtcenter.org/terms-of-service), which governs your use of the Service. By using our Service, you consent to our Privacy Policy and [Terms of Service](https://lalgbtcenter.org/terms-of-service) and our collection, use and sharing of your information and data, and other activities, as described below.

**Linkable Table of Contents**

**It is important that you read and understand the entire Privacy Policy before using the Service. To ease review, each section below contains a brief introductory summary and a link to the full explanation. Click on the headings and the “More” buttons to be taken to the full explanation. Any capitalized terms that appear in but are not otherwise defined in the introduction have the meanings given to them elsewhere in the Privacy Policy.**

**1.** [ What Information Does the Service Collect?](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section1)

We collect and receive certain information about you as you interact with our Service, explained further in this section. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section1)

  1. [Information You Provide to Us](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section1)

We may collect certain Personal Information and Demographic Information that you provide to us when you interact with the Service. For example, we may collect this information through various forms and in various places on the Service, including newsletter registration forms, through “contact us” forms, or when you otherwise interact with the Service. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section1a)

  2. [Information Collected and Stored As You Access and Use the Service](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section1b)

Certain information may be collected from you automatically when you access and use the Service. For example, we and third parties may use Tracking Technologies to collect Usage Information for a variety of purposes, including serving you advertising, based on your having visited our Service or your activities across time and third party locations. We do not look for or respond to do not track signals, but you may have certain other options regarding tracking and/or targeting. This section provides details on:

    * Usage Information
    * Tracking Technologies
    * Tracking Technologies Usage
    * Tracking Technologies Choices and Consent
    * Third Party Tracking and Do Not Track
  3. [Information Third Parties Provide About You  
](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section1c)  
We may obtain information about you from third parties.[ More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section1c)
  4. [Third-Party Content and Services  
](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section1d)  
If you interact with third-party services, those services may send us information about you and you or we may send them information about you. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section1d)
  5. [Information You Provide About a Third Party  
](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section1e)  
You may provide us information about others, such as when you send a friend a message. If so, the information you provide (names, e-mail addresses, etc.) may be used to facilitate the communication, but will not be used for other marketing purposes unless your friend consents. You may be identified to the friend in connection with such a message. [More  
](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section1e)

**2.** [How Do We Use The Information Collected?](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section2)

We use your Personal Information, Demographic Information and Usage Information for a variety of purposes detailed in this section including:

  * Generally
  * Advertising
  * Contact Us
  * Use of Information For Recruitment Purposes

**3.**[ How and When Do We Share Information With Third Parties?](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3)

We may provide your information to third parties under various circumstances detailed in this section. These may include:

[(a) When You Request Information From or Provide Information to Third Parties](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3a)

If you request information from third parties, request that we send information to third parties or interact with third-party services, content, ads or tools (including Facebook and other third party share functionality) we may share your information with such parties and/or they may collect your information directly. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3a)

Our vendors may collect your information on our behalf or we may share it with them so that they may provide services to us and you. Some may offer you choices regarding the collection and use of your information. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3b)

We may share or transfer your content and information in connection with the Service to target and deliver content and advertisements to you and other users, both on and off of our Service. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3c)

When you make a donation through the Service or offline we collect Personal Information in order to process and complete the donation. We may also share your information with third parties as part of a cooperative database with those third parties and for those third parties’ direct marketing and/or charitable solicitation purposes, unless you opt out. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3d)

There are a variety of administrative and legal reasons for which we may share some or all of your information.[ More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3e)

We may share your information with our affiliates or in the event of a sale, merger or similar transaction.[ More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3f)

Promotions entrants may be required to consent to certain information sharing. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3g)

Certain employment application, self-identifying information (e.g., race and gender) may be shared with the government and other third parties. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3h)

We may from time to time elect to share certain information about you collected by us on the Service or offline with third parties as part of a cooperative database with those third parties and for those third parties’ direct marketing and/or charitable solicitation purposes, subject to your ability to opt-out. California residents can get more information. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3i)

**4.** [What About Information I Disclose Publicly or to Others?](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section4)

Posting content in public areas makes it available to others. We may share and use your public information for any reason not otherwise prohibited by this Privacy Policy. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section4a)

You grant us the right to use your name and likeness in connection with your posting and activities. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section4b)

**5.** [Do Third-Party Content, Links to Third-Party Sites and/or Third-Party Apps Appear on the Service?](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section5)

We may allow you to access third-party content on the Service, or to link to third-party applications and locations from the Service, but we are not responsible for your interaction with third-party content, apps, and locations. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section5)

**6.** [Are Ads Served on the Service Or Retargeted to Me Later?](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section6)

We and third parties may send you ads, including targeted ads based on your location, information and/or behavior. If you object, do not use our Service and/or exercise choices some third parties may offer. [ More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section6)

**7.** [ How Do I Exercise Choice and Change Preferences?](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section7)

You may change certain account information, and exercise certain choices regarding information collection and communications preferences, including exercising certain marketing opt-outs, as more fully detailed in this section. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section7)

**8.** [What About Transfer of Information to the United States?](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section8)

You consent to your data being transferred to the United States, which has different data protection laws than other countries. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section8)

**9.** [What Should Parents Know About Children?](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section9)

We are a non-profit and not subject to the parental notice and consent requirements of federal law. However, California minors have certain rights regarding removal of their posts. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section9)

**10.**[ What About Security?](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section10)

No data security is absolute, but we endeavor to take reasonable steps to secure data appropriately. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section10)

**11.** [What About Changes to the Privacy Policy?](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section11)

We may change this Privacy Policy upon posting of a revised Privacy Policy. However, we will continue to treat your Personal Information under the terms of the privacy policy in effect when it was collected unless you otherwise consent. [More](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section11)

**The Full Detailed Privacy Policy**

**1.** **What Information Does the Service Collect?**

**(a) Information You Provide to Us**

**Personal Information and Demographic Information.** On the Service, we may ask you to provide us with certain categories of information such as: (1) personally identifiable information, which is information that identifies you personally, such as your first and last name, e-mail address, and home address ( **“Personal Information”** ); and (2) demographic information, such as information about your gender, age, marital status, and occupation ( **“Demographic Information”** ). We may collect this information through various forms and in various places on the Service, including donation form, contact us forms, or when you otherwise interact with the Service. To the extent we combine Demographic Information with your Personal Information we collect directly from you on the Service, we will treat the combined data as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

**(b) Information Collected or Stored As You Access and Use the Service**

**Generally.**

In addition to any Personal Information or other information that you choose to submit to us via our Service, we and our third-party service providers may use a variety of technologies that automatically (or passively) store or collect certain information whenever you visit or interact with the Service ( **“Usage Information”** ). This Usage Information may be stored or accessed using a variety of technologies that may be downloaded to your personal computer, browser, laptop, tablet, mobile phone or other device (a **“Device”** ) whenever you visit or interact with our Service. To the extent we associate Usage Information with your Personal Information we collect directly from you on the Service, we will treat it as Personal Information This Usage Information may include:

    * your IP address, UDID, advertising identifier or other unique identifier (“Device Identifier”). A Device Identifier is a number that is automatically assigned to your Device used to access the Service, and our computers identifyyour Device by its Device Identifier;
    * your Device functionality (including browser, operating system, hardware, mobile network information);
    * the URL that referred you to our Service;
    * the areas within our Service that you visit and your activities there, including remembering you and your preferences;
    * your Device location;
    * your Device characteristics;and
    * certain other Device data, including the time of day, among other information.

**Tracking Technologies.** We may use various methods and technologies to store or collect Usage Information ( **“Tracking Technologies”** ). Tracking Technologies may set, change, alter or modify settings or configurations on your Device. A few of the Tracking Technologies include, without limitation, the following (and subsequent technology and methods later developed):

**Cookies.** A cookie is a data file placed on a Device when it is used to visit the Service. A Flash cookie (or locally shared object) is a data file placed on a Device via the Adobe Flash plug-in that may be built-in to or downloaded by you to your Device. HTML5 cookies can be programmed through HTML5 local storage.

**Web Beacons.** Small graphic images or other web programming code called web beacons (also known as “1x1 GIFs” or “clear GIFs”) may be included in our Service’s pages and messages. Web beacons may be invisible to you, but any electronic image or other web programming code inserted into a page or e-mail can act as a web beacon. Web beacons or similar technologies may be used for a number of purposes, including, without limitation, to count visitors to the Service, to monitor how users navigate the Service, to count how many e-mails that were sent were actually opened or to count how many particular articles or links were actually viewed.

**Embedded Scripts.** An embedded script is programming code that is designed to collect information about your interactions with the Service, such as the links you click on. The code is temporarily downloaded onto your Device from our web server or a third party service provider, is active only while you are connected to the Service, and is deactivated or deleted thereafter.

**Browser Fingerprinting.** Collection and analysis of information from your Device, such as, without limitation, your operating system, plug-ins, system fonts and other data, for purposes of identification.

**ETag, or Entity Tag.** A feature of the cache in browsers. It is an opaque identifier assigned by a web server to a specific version of a resource found at a URL. If the resource content at that URL ever changes, a new and different ETag is assigned. Used in this manner ETags are a form of Device Identifier. ETag tracking may generate unique tracking values even where the consumer blocks HTTP, Flash, and/or HTML5 cookies.

**Recognition Technologies.** Technologies, including application of statistical probability to data sets, which attempt to recognize or make assumptions about users and devices (e.g., that a user of multiple devices is the same user).

**Location-identifying Technologies.** Additionally, the Service may use GPS (global positioning systems) software and other location-based technologies to locate you so we may verify your location and deliver you relevant content based on your location.

**In-app Tracking Methods.** There are a variety of Tracking Technologies that may be included in mobile applications, and these are not browser-based like cookies and cannot be controlled by browser settings. Some use device identifiers such as “Ad IDs” to associate app user activity to a particular app.

There may be other Tracking Technologies now and later devised and used by us in connection with the Service.

**Tracking Technologies Usage.** We may use Tracking Technologies for a variety of purposes, including:

**Strictly Necessary.** We may use cookies or other Tracking Technologies that we consider are strictly necessary to allow you to use and access our Service, including cookies required to prevent fraudulent activity, improve security or allow you to make use of shopping cart functionality.

**Performance Related.** We may use cookies or other Tracking Technologies that are useful in order to assess the performance of the Service, including as part of our analytic practices or otherwise to improve the content, products or services offered through the Service.

**Functionality Related.** We may use cookies or other Tracking Technologies that are required to offer you enhanced functionality when accessing the Service, including identifying you when you sign in to our Service or keeping track of our specified preferences, including in terms of the presentation of content on our Service.

**Targeting Related.** We may use Tracking Technologies to deliver content, including ads, relevant to your interests on our Service and third party sites based on how you interact with advertisements or content. This includes using Tracking Technologies to understand the usefulness to you of the content that has been delivered to you. Further information on this, and your opt-out choices, is found in [Section 6](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section6) and [Section 7](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section7).

**Tracking Technologies Choices and Consent.**

We are giving you detailed notice of the Tracking Technologies and your limited choices regarding them so that your consent is meaningfully informed. For more information on your choices regarding Tracking Technologies, see [Section 6 ](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section6)and [Section 7 ](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section7)below.

**Third Party Tracking and Do Not Track.**

Third parties may use Tracking Technologies in connection with our Service, which may include the collection of information about your online activities over time and across third-party web sites or online services. We may not control those Tracking Technologies and we are not responsible for them. However, you consent to potentially encountering third party Tracking Technologies in connection with use of our Service. Statements regarding our practices do not apply to the methods for collecting information used by these third-parties and others or the use of the information that such third parties collect. The relevant third party’s terms of service, privacy policy, permissions, notices and choices should be reviewed regarding their collection, storage and sharing practices. We make no representations regarding the policies or practices of third-party advertisers or advertising networks or exchanges or related third parties. For more information on our vendors, and their Tracking Technologies, click[ here](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section3b). For more information on advertising and advertisers, and related Tracking Technologies, click [here](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section6). For more information on your choices regarding Tracking Technologies click [here](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section7).

Also, various third parties are developing or have developed signals or other mechanisms known as “do not track signals”. For instance, some browsers may have such signal options, though they differ as to if the signal is set as default or must be turned on by the user. Further, there is not yet an industry consensus as to what site and app operators should do with regard to these signals. Accordingly, we do not monitor or take any action with respect to these signals or other mechanisms, though we may consider doing so if an understandable and practical standard is developed and widely adopted. For more information on “do not track” visit [http://www.allaboutdnt.com.](http://www.allaboutdnt.com./)

[](http://www.allaboutdnt.com./)**(c) Information Third Parties Provide About You**

We may receive information about you from your friends and others that use the Service, such as when they submit content to us or post on the Service. Additionally, we may, from time to time, supplement the information we collect directly from you on our Service with outside records from third parties for various purposes, including to enhance our ability to serve you, to tailor our content to you and to offer you opportunities that may be of interest to you. To the extent we combine information we receive from those sources with your Personal Information we collect on the Service, it will be treated as Personal Information and we will apply this Privacy Policy to such combined information, unless we have disclosed otherwise. In no other circumstances do our statements under this Privacy Policy apply to information we receive about you from third parties.

**(d) Third-Party Content and Services**

The Service may include functionality that allows certain kinds of interactions between the Service and a third-party web site, platform, tool, application or other service, and/or accessing or display of third-party content via the Service ( **“Third Party Services”** ). The use of Third Party Services may involve the third-party operator thereof ( **“Third Party Operator”** ) providing certain information, including Personal Information, to us. For example, when you register with the Service, you may have an option to use your Facebook, Google or other account provided by a third-party site or application to facilitate the registration and log-in or transaction process on the Service, or otherwise link accounts.

If we offer and you choose to use Third Party Services to access or use our Service, the Third Party Services may send Personal Information about you to us. To the extent we combine such third-party sourced information with Personal Information we collect directly from you on the Service, we will treat the combined information as Personal Information under this Privacy Policy. If we discontinue use of any Third Party Service (e.g., your Facebook or any other account as an access mechanism for the Service), you consent that we may nevertheless retain any Personal Information, and other information and data, we may have already received in connection therewith in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

In addition, we may provide Third Party Services’ interfaces or links on the Service to facilitate your sending a communication from the Service. For example, we may use third parties to facilitate e-mails, tweets, “likes,” content submissions or postings of comments on Facebook or other social media platforms. We may also enable access to or display of third party content via the Service, that is actually being served or published by the third party, and such third party may be collecting data from you in connection with that content. These third parties may collect and retain any information used or provided in any such communications or other activities and these third parties’ practices are not subject to our Privacy Policy.

When you use Third Party Services, you are using their services and not our Service and they, not we, are responsible for their practices. You should review the applicable third party privacy policies before using such Third Party Services in connection with our Service. For more information on Third Party Services and the policies and activities of Third Party Operators see [Section 5](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section5).

**(e) Information You Provide About a Third Party**

You may send someone else a communication from the Service, such as sending an invitation to a friend. If so, the information you provide (names, e-mail addresses, etc.) is used to facilitate the communication and is not used by us for any other marketing purpose unless we obtain consent from that person or we explicitly say otherwise. Please be aware that when you use any send-to-a-friend functionality on our Service, your contact information, name or user name and message may be included in the communication sent to your addressee(s). Some of these tools may be third-party tools subject to third-party privacy policies.

**2\. How Do We Use the Information Collected?**

**Generally.** We may use your Personal Information, Demographic Information and/or Usage Information that we collect about you: (1) to provide you with information or services or process transactions that you have requested or agreed to receive, including to send you electronic newsletters, or to provide you with special offers or promotional materials on behalf of us or third parties; (2) to enable you to participate in a variety of the Service’s features including online entry sweepstakes, contests or other promotions; (3) to process your registration with any of the Service, including verifying your information is active and valid; (4) to manage and administer the Service including account management, and billing and collections activities; (5) to improve the Service or create new service offerings, to customize your experience on any of the Service, or to serve you, or suggest to you, specific content that may be most relevant to you; (6) to contact you with regard to your use of any of the Service and, in our discretion, changes to the any of the Service and/or any of the Service’s’ policies; (7) to prevent unauthorized, improper or illegal activities on the Service; (8) for internal business purposes; and (9) for purposes disclosed at the time you provide your information or as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy or for any other legal purpose not inconsistent with this Privacy Policy or our [Terms of Service](https://lalgbtcenter.org/terms-of-service).

**Advertising.** We may also use your Personal Information, Demographic Information or Usage Information that we collect about you: (1) to specifically target relevant advertisements or content to you, including making recommendations based on your activities; (2) to understand the usefulness to you of the advertisements or content that have been delivered to you; and (3) when you comment to or add content to the Service. For more on advertising, see [Section 6](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section6), and for information on your choices regarding advertising, see [Section 7 ](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section7)below.

**Contact Us.** Please note that information submitted to any of the Services via a “contact us” or other similar customer inquiry function may not receive a response. We will not use the information provided by you in a customer inquiry communication to contact you for marketing purposes unrelated to your request unless you agree otherwise.

**Use of Information for Recruitment Purposes.** Where you have provided us with Personal Information or Demographic Information as part of an online application for employment or internship, we may use that information in order to allow us to make an informed decision about whether to proceed with your application. We may, as part of this recruitment process, collect information about your education, employment history and similar matters. Where this Personal Information or Demographic Information is considered to be sensitive, you expressly consent to our processing of this information for recruitment purposes by submitting it to us.

**3\. How and When Do We Share Information with Third Parties?** We may share **“Non-Personal Information”** (i.e., information that is not or is modified not to be Personal Information), such as aggregated user statistics, with third parties. For instance, if we de-identify data about you, it is not treated as Personal Information by us, and we may share it with others freely. Except where prohibited by applicable law, we may share your Device Identifiers with third parties along with data (other than Personal Information) related to you and your activities as non-Personal Information under this Privacy Policy.

We may share the information we have collected about you, including Personal Information, as disclosed at the time you provide your information and as described below, as set forth in our [Terms of Service](https://lalgbtcenter.org/terms-of-service) or any applicable Additional Terms, or for any other reason not prohibited by applicable law or inconsistent with this Privacy Policy. Without limitation of the forgoing, we may disclose your information, including Personal Information, as follows:

**(a)** **When You Request Information From or Provide Information to Third Parties.** You may be presented with an option on our Service to receive certain information and/or marketing offers directly from third parties or to have us send certain information to third parties or give them access to it. If you choose to do so, your Personal Information and other information may be disclosed to such third parties and all information you disclose will be subject to the third-party privacy policies and practices of such third parties. In addition, third parties may store, collect or otherwise have access to your information when you interact with their Tracking Technologies, content, tools, apps or ads on our Service or link to them from our Service. This may include using third-party tools such as Facebook, Twitter, Pinterest or other third-party posting or content sharing tools and by so interacting you consent to such third party practices. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of such third parties and, therefore, you should review such third-party privacy policies and practices of such third parties prior to requesting information from or otherwise interacting with them.

**(b)** **Third Parties Providing Services on Our Behalf.** We may use third-party vendors to perform certain services on behalf of us or the Service, such as hosting the Service, designing and/or operating the Service’s features, tracking the Service’s activities and analytics, and enabling us to perform other administrative services. We may provide these vendors with access to user information, including Device Identifiers and Personal Information, to carry out the services they are performing for you or for us. Third-party analytics and other service providers may set and access their own Tracking Technologies on your Device and they may otherwise collect or have access to information about you, potentially including Personal Information, about you. We are not responsible for those third party technologies or activities arising out of them. However, some may offer you certain choices regarding their practices. For more information, see [Section 7(b)](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section7b) below.

**(c)** **To Deliver Advertising.** We, and others we work with (e.g., third party publishers, advertisers and advertising services providers) may use your Personal Information, Demographic Information and/or Usage Information we have collected in connection with the Service to target and deliver content and advertisements to you and other users, both on and off of our Service.

**(d)** **When You Make a Donation.** When you make a donation through the Service or offline we collect Personal Information in order to process and complete the donation. We may also share your personal information with third parties as part of a cooperative database with those third parties and for those third parties’ direct marketing and/or charitable solicitation purposes. At any time, you have the option to opt-out on a going forward basis of our sharing of your personal information with third parties as part of a cooperative database with those third parties and for those third parties’ direct marketing and/or charitable solicitation purposes by e-mailing us [here](https://lalgbtcenter.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#5635393b263a3f373835333930303f3533163a373a31342235333822332478392431) or writing to us at Los Angeles LGBT Center, McDonald/Wright Building, 1625 N Schrader Blvd, Los Angeles, CA 90028-6213, Attn: Compliance Officer.

**(e)** **To Protect the Rights of The Center and Others.** To the fullest extent permitted by applicable law, we may also disclose your information if we believe in good faith that doing so is necessary or appropriate to: (i) protect or defend the rights, safety or property of The Center or third parties (including through the enforcement of this Policy, our [Terms of Service](https://lalgbtcenter.org/terms-of-service), and other applicable agreements and policies); or (ii) comply with legal and regulatory obligations (e.g., pursuant to law enforcement inquiries, subpoenas or court orders). To the fullest extent permitted by applicable law, we have complete discretion in electing to make or not make such disclosures, and to contest or not contest requests for such disclosures, all without notice to you.

**(f) Affiliates and Business Transfer.** We may share your information, including your Device Identifiers and Personal Information, Demographic Information and Usage Information with our affiliates **(“Affiliates”)**. We also reserve the right to disclose and transfer all such information: (i) to a subsequent owner, co-owner or operator of the Service or applicable database; or (ii) in connection with a merger, consolidation, restructuring, the sale of substantially all of our interests and/or assets or other corporate change, including, during the course of any due diligence process.

**(g) Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions.** We may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions (any, a **“Promotion”** ) through the Service that may require registration. By participating in a Promotion, you are agreeing to official rules that govern that Promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, allowing the sponsor of the Promotion to use your name, voice and/or likeness in advertising or marketing associated with the Promotion. If you choose to enter a Promotion, Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties or the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, including, in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, and as required by law or permitted by the Promotion’s official rules, such as on a winners list.

**(h) EEOC/Affirmative Action Reporting.** In conjunction with laws and regulations enforced by the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission ( **“EEOC”** ), the Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs ( **“OFCCP”** ) and similar state and local regulatory agencies, we may ask you to provide us with self-identifying information (such as veteran status, gender and ethnicity). Providing such self-identifying information is voluntary, but if you do provide us with such information, we may submit that information, to the EEOC, the OFCCP and similar state and local regulatory agencies or otherwise use or disclose it for business-related purposes, including, without limitation, responding to information requests, fulfilling regulatory reporting requirements and defending against employment related complaints.

**(i) Your California Privacy Rights.** We may from time to time elect to share certain information about you collected by us on the Service or offline with third parties as part of a cooperative database with those third parties and for those third parties’ direct marketing and/or charitable solicitation purposes. California Civil Code Section 1798.83 permits California residents who have supplied personal information, as defined in the statute, to us to, under certain circumstances, opt-out on a going forward basis of such sharing. If you are a California resident, you may exercise this opt-out or inquire further about how we comply with Section 1798.83 by e-mailing us [here](https://lalgbtcenter.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#afccc0c2dfc3c6cec1cccac0c9c9c6cccaefc3cec3c8cddbcccac1dbcadd81c0ddc8) or writing to us at Los Angeles LGBT Center, McDonald/Wright Building, 1625 N Schrader Blvd, Los Angeles, CA 90028-6213, Attn: Compliance Officer. Any such request must include “California Privacy Rights Request” in the first line of the description and include your name, street address, city, state, and ZIP code. Please note that we are only required to respond to one request per customer each year, and we are not required to respond to requests made by means other than through this e-mail address or mail address. California minors should see [Section 9 ](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section9)regarding removal of certain content they have posted.

**4\. What About Information I Disclose Publicly Or To Others?**

**(a) User-Generated Content and Public Information.** The Service may permit you to submit ideas, photographs, user profiles, writings, music, video, audio recordings, computer graphics, pictures, data, questions, comments, suggestions or other content, including Personal Information (collectively, **“User Content”** ), such as on blogs and message boards. We or others may store, display, reproduce, publish, distribute or otherwise use User Content online or offline in any media or format (currently existing or hereafter developed) and may or may not attribute it to you. Others may have access to this User Content and may have the ability to share it with third parties. Please think carefully before deciding what information you share, including Personal Information, in connection with your User Content. Please note that The Center does not control who will have access to the information that you choose to make public, and cannot ensure that parties who have access to such publicly available information will respect your privacy or keep it secure. We are not responsible for the privacy or security of any information that you make publicly available on the Service or what others do with information you share with them on the Service. We are not responsible for the accuracy, use or misuse of any User Content that you disclose or receive from third parties through the Service.

**(b) Name and Likeness.** We may also publish your name, voice, likeness and other Personal Information that is part of your User Content, and we may use the content, or any portion of the content, for advertising, marketing, publicity and promotional activities. For full terms and conditions regarding User Content you submit to the Service, please review our [Terms of Service](https://lalgbtcenter.org/terms-of-service).

**5\. Do Third-Party Content, Links To Third-Party Sites, and/or Third-Party Apps Appear on the Service?**

The Service may contain content that is supplied by a Third Party Operator, and those third parties may collect Usage Information and your Device Identifier when such content is served to you. Third Party Services may also be available via the Service. We are not responsible for the data collection and privacy practices employed by such third parties or their services and they may be collecting data about you and may be sharing it with us and/or others. These third parties and their services may also associate their Tracking Technologies with you, track you across sites and time, serve you their own ads (including Interest-based Ads (defined below)) and may or may not have their own published privacy policies.

In addition, when you are on the Service you may be directed to other services that are operated and controlled by third parties that we do not control. For example, if you “click” on a link, the “click” may take you off the Service onto a different site. We encourage you to note when you leave our Service and to review the third-party privacy policies of all third-party locations and exercise caution in connection with them.

Be sure to review any available privacy policies and notices before submitting any Personal Information to a third party or its services, or otherwise interacting with Third Party Services or other locations you link to from our Service, and exercise caution in connection with them. We are not responsible for the availability, completeness or accuracy of such third parties’ policies or notices.

**6\. Are Ads Served On the Service or Retargeted to Me Later?**

The Center may engage and work with third parties to serve advertisements on The Center’s behalf on the Service, and/or on Third Party Services, and to provide analytics about the use of the Service and the performance of The Center’s ads and content on the Service and on Third Party Services. In addition, The Center may participate in online advertising networks and exchanges that display relevant advertisements to The Center visitors, on the Service and on Third Party Services, based on user interests as reflected in their use of the Service and certain Third Party Services. These entities may use cookies and other Tracking Technologies to automatically collect information about you and your activities, such as registering a unique identifier for your device and tying that to your online activities on and off of the Service. The Center may use this information to, among other things, analyze and track data, determine the popularity of certain content, deliver advertising and content targeted to your interests on the Service and Third Party Services and better understand your online activity.

Some information about your use of the Service and certain Third Party Services may be collected using Tracking Technologies across time and services and used by The Center and third parties for purposes such as to associate different devices you use, and deliver relevant and retargeted ads (“Interest-based Ads”) and/or other content to you on the Service and certain Third Party Services. You may have certain choices regarding these activities as explained in the next section.

The Center is not responsible for third parties or Third Party Services associated with advertising and analytics services, and related tracking activities. Consult their privacy policies and notices for information on their practices and see [Section 7](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section7) regarding certain choices some of them may offer you. Your browser settings may allow you to automatically transmit a “Do Not Track” signal to online services you visit. Note, however, The Center currently does not alter The Center’s practices when The Center receives a “Do Not Track” signal from a visitor’s browser. For more information on tracking and “do not track,” see [Section 1(b)](https://lalgbtcenter.org/administrative/privacy-policy#section1b).

**7\. How Do I Exercise Choice and Change Preferences?**

**(a) Accessing And Changing Information.**

The Service may provide web pages or other mechanisms allowing you to delete, correct or update some of the Personal Information you have provided The Center. The Center will make good faith efforts to make requested changes in The Center’s then-active databases as soon as practicable, but it is not always possible to completely change, remove or delete all of your information or public postings from The Center’s databases and residual and/or cached data may remain archived thereafter. Further, we reserve the right to retain data (i) as required by applicable law; and (ii) for so long as reasonably necessary to fulfill the purposes for which the data is retained as permitted by applicable law (e.g., business records).

**(b) Tracking Technologies Generally.**

Regular cookies may generally be disabled or removed by tools available as part of most commercial browsers, and in some instances blocked in the future by selecting certain settings. Browsers offer different functionalities and options so you may need to set them separately. Also, tools from commercial browsers may not be effective with regard to Flash cookies (also known as locally shared objects), HTML5 cookies or other Tracking Technologies. For information on disabling Flash cookies, go to Adobe’s website [http://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-third-party-local-shared.html.](https://helpx.adobe.com/flash-player/kb/disable-third-party-local-shared.html.) Please be aware that if you disable or remove these technologies some parts of the Service may not work and that when you revisit the Service your ability to limit browser-based Tracking Technologies is subject to your browser settings and limitations.

App-related Tracking Technologies in connection with non-browser usage (e.g., most functionality of a mobile app) can be disabled by uninstalling our apps. To uninstall our apps, follow the instructions from your operating system or handset manufacturer. In addition, you may have certain choices regarding in-app Interest-based Advertising as described in the next section.

Some third parties may also offer you choices regarding their Tracking Technologies. One way to potentially identify cookies on our Site is to add the free Ghostery plug-in to your browser ([www.ghostery.com](https://www.ghostery.com/)), which according to Ghostery will display for you traditional, browser-based cookies associated with the web sites (but not mobile apps) you visit and privacy and opt-out policies and options of the parties operating those cookies. The Center is not responsible for the completeness or accuracy of this tool or third party choice notices or mechanisms. For specific information on some of the choice options offered by third party analytics and advertising providers, see the next section.

**(c) Analytics and Interest-Based Advertising.**

The Center may use Google Analytics or other Service Providers for analytics services. These analytics services may use cookies and other Tracking Technologies to help The Center analyze how users use the Service. Information generated by these services (e.g., your IP address and other Usage Information) may be transmitted to and stored by Google Analytics and other Service Providers on servers in the U.S. (or elsewhere) and these Service Providers may use this information for purposes such as evaluating your use of the Service, compiling statistic reports on the Service’s activity, and providing other services relating to Service activity and other Internet usage. The Center only retains aggregated data from Google Analytics. You may exercise choices regarding the use of cookies from Google Analytics by going to <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout> or downloading the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on.

Certain companies may participate in the Digital Advertising Alliance ( **"DAA"** ) AdChoices Program and may display an Advertising Option Icon for Interest-based Ads that links to an opt-out tool which allows you to exercise certain choices regarding targeting. You can learn more about the DAA AdChoices Program at <http://www.youradchoices.com/> and its opt-out program for mobile apps at <http://www.aboutads.info/appchoices.> In addition, certain advertising networks and exchanges may participate in the Network Advertising Initiative ( **“NAI”** ). NAI has developed a tool that allows consumers to opt out of certain Interest-based Ads delivered by NAI members' ad networks. To learn more about opting out of such targeted advertising or to use the NAI tool, see [http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/.](https://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) Please be aware that, even if you are able to opt out of certain kinds of Interest-based Ads, you will continue to receive non-targeted ads. Further, opting out of one or more NAI or DAA members only means that those selected members should no longer under the DAA / NAI rules deliver certain targeted ads to you. This will affect this and other services, but does not mean you will no longer receive any targeted content and/or ads (e.g., from other ad networks). Also, if your browsers are configured to reject cookies when you visit this opt-out page, or you subsequently erase your cookies, use a different Device or web browser(s), or use a non-browser-based method of access (e.g., mobile app), your NAI / DAA browser-based opt-out may not, or may no longer, be effective. Mobile device opt-outs will not affect browser-based Interest-based Ads even on the same device, and you must opt-out separately for each device. The Center is not responsible for the effectiveness of, or compliance with, any third-parties’ opt-out options or programs or the accuracy of their statements regarding their programs. However, The Center supports the ad industry’s **2009 Self-regulatory Principles for Online Behavioral Advertising** (<http://www.iab.net/media/file/ven-principles-07-01-09.pdf>) and expect that ad networks The Center directly engages to serve you Interest-based Ads will do so as well, though The Center cannot guaranty their compliance.

**(d) Mobile Apps.**

With respect to The Center’s apps, you can stop all collection of information by uninstalling the app. Also, you may be able to exercise specific privacy choices, such as enabling or disabling certain location-based services, by adjusting the permissions in your mobile device. See also the prior section regarding in-app Interest-based Ads choices.

**(e) Communications and Marketing.**

You can opt out of receiving certain promotional communications (e-mails or text messaging) from The Center at any time by (i) for promotional e-mails, by following the instructions as provided in e-mails to click on the unsubscribe link, or if available by changing your communication preferences by logging onto your account; and (ii) for text messages, by following the instructions as provided in text messages from The Center to text the word, “STOP”. Please note that your opt-out is limited to the e-mail address or phone number used and will not affect subsequent subscriptions. If you opt-out of only certain communications, other subscriptions may continue. Even if you opt out of receiving promotional communications, The Center may, subject to applicable law, continue to send you non-promotional communications, such as those about your account, transactions, servicing, or The Center’s ongoing business relations. In addition, you may opt-out of our future sharing of your personal information with third parties as part of a cooperative database with those third parties and for those third parties’ direct marketing and/or charitable purposes by e-mailing us [here](https://lalgbtcenter.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#99faf6f4e9f5f0f8f7fafcf6fffff0fafcd9f5f8f5fefbedfafcf7edfcebb7f6ebfe) or writing to us at Los Angeles LGBT Center, McDonald/Wright Building, 1625 N Schrader Blvd, Los Angeles, CA 90028-6213, Attn: Compliance Officer.

If you have any questions about the Privacy Policy or practices described in it, you should contact us in the following ways:

Postal Mail:

Los Angeles LGBT Center  
McDonald/Wright Building  
1625 N Schrader Blvd  
Los Angeles, CA 90028-6213  
Attn: Compliance Officer

By e-mail [here](https://lalgbtcenter.org/cdn-cgi/l/email-protection#9ffcf0f2eff3f6fef1fcfaf0f9f9f6fcfadff3fef3f8fdebfcfaf1ebfaedb1f0edf8)

**8\. What About Transfer of Information to the United States?**

Our Service is operated in the United States and intended for users located in the United States. If you are located outside of the United States, please be aware that information we collect, including Personal Information, will be transferred to, and processed, stored and used in the United States. The data protection laws in the United States may differ from those of the country in which you are located, and your Personal Information may be subject to access requests from governments, courts, or law enforcement in the United States according to laws of the United States. By using the Service or providing us with any information, you consent to the transfer to, and processing, usage, sharing and storage of your information, including Personal Information, in the United States as set forth in this Privacy Policy.

**9\. What Should Parents Know About Children?**

We are a non-profit and not subject to the parental notice and consent requirements under the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act ( **“COPPA”** ).

Any California residents under the age of eighteen (18) who have registered to use the Service, and who have posted content or information on the Service, can request that such information be removed from the Service by contacting us at the e-mail or address set forth in the “Communications and Marketing” section above making such a request, stating that they personally posted such content or information and detailing where the content or information is posted. We will make reasonable good faith efforts to remove the post from prospective public view or anonymize it so the minor cannot be individually identified. This removal process cannot ensure complete or comprehensive removal. For instance, third-parties may have republished the post and archived copies of it may be stored by search engines and others that we do not control.

**10\. What About Security?**

We endeavor to incorporate commercially reasonable safeguards to help protect and secure your Personal Information. However, no data transmission over the Internet, mobile networks, wireless transmission or electronic storage of information can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. Please note that we cannot ensure the security of any information you transmit to us, and you use our Service and provide us with your information at your own risk.

**11\. What About Changes to the Privacy Policy?**

We reserve the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. Any changes will be effective immediately upon the posting of the revised Privacy Policy and your use of our Service indicates your consent to the privacy policy posted at the time of use. However, we will not use your previously collected Personal Information in a manner materially different than represented at the time it was collected without your consent. To the extent any provision of this Privacy Policy is found by a competent tribunal to be invalid or unenforceable, such provision shall be severed to the extent necessary for the remainder to be valid and enforceable.
